<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zero Degrees Kelvin</title>
    <link>https://jasonvella.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zero Degrees Kelvin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 21:48:53 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasonvella.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scrumfall</title>
      <link>https://jasonvella.com/posts/scrumfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 21:48:53 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonvella.com/posts/scrumfall/</guid>
      
        <description>A while ago in a company I worked for I noticed something strange. We were doing all the ceremonies of Scrum with the sprint plannings and retros and so on, yet we seemed to be moving intolerably slowly. Everything took forever to get to prod and was often not in good shape by the time it got there.
Looking up into the management layer, executives and board members were wanting to know what we were dropping over the next few quarters, what big splash features we planned to implement, and how they would attract further investment.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Your CV Stand Out</title>
      <link>https://jasonvella.com/posts/makeyourcvstandout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 22:22:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonvella.com/posts/makeyourcvstandout/</guid>
      
        <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve sometimes taken the opportunity to speak on engineering career panels and a question often asked by new engineers or graduates is &amp;lsquo;How do I make my CV stand out?&amp;rsquo; The answers given are often of a similar ilk - write a cover letter, research the company, make sure the employer understands why you&amp;rsquo;re excited about their particular business. Whilst this is great advice, it may or may not make you stand out.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Degrees Kelvin</title>
      <link>https://jasonvella.com/posts/zerodegreeskelvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 22:46:10 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonvella.com/posts/zerodegreeskelvin/</guid>
      
        <description>It seems fitting that the first post should be about the inspiration for its title.
The physics nerds in the room can skip to the next paragraph. Zero Kelvin (-273.15C), otherwise known as absolute zero, is the coldest possible temperature in the universe. It is also impossible to reach. When you draw heat out of an object it immediately warms the surrounding environment preventing the object from ever reaching 0k. We&amp;rsquo;ve gotten very, very close &amp;hellip; but never quite there.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Am I?</title>
      <link>https://jasonvella.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:25:10 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonvella.com/about/</guid>
      
        <description>I am a software professional and leader who often finds myself drawing analogies with the non-software world. I like to use these as a tool to both remember and explain my ideas in non-technical terms which I find helps level the playing field when dealing with audiences with mixed levels of technical knowledge.
The name of this blog is one such analogy. We can never reach zero degrees Kelvin but it still exists.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>